A Guide to the Arts, Education and Americans Panel records FA082
Rockefeller Archive Center
The Arts, Education and Americans Panel records
1958-1979 (bulk 1972-1979)
bulk
Rockefeller Archive Center
Arts, Education, and Americans Panel
American Council for the Arts in Education
FA082
20.6 Cubic Feet 48 boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for scholarly research without restriction.
Arrangement note
The records of the Panel are divided into six series:
Series 1 - General Records
Series 2 - Arts, Education and Americans Panel (AEA)
Series 3 - Panel Report
Series 4 - Norris Houghton Files
Series 5 - Financial Records
Series 1041 - Photographs
Biographical/Historical note
The American Council for the Arts in Education (hereafter ACAE) was incorporated as a non-profit organization under the laws of the State of Ohio on January 31, 1972. It was the successor organization to the National Council for the Arts in Education (hereafter NCAIE), which had been founded in 1958. Neither the ACAE nor its parent organization were grant-making institutions; both organizations were primarily engaged in study activities intended to promote the arts as an integral part of the general school curriculum.
At its inception, the ACAE inherited the Arts/Worth Program from the NCAIE. This program received its impetus from the August 1969 Wingspread Conference and was designed "to alter American opinion about the place of the arts in the educational process." Under the direction of Alan Sapp and Joseph C. Sloane, the Arts/Worth Program engaged in a number of promotional and survey activities until financial pressures brought about its demise in 1974.
In 1974, Norris Houghton became president of the ACAE. Under his leadership, the organization tapped new sources of funding and designed its last major project: the Arts, Education and Americans Panel. The Panel was headed by David Rockefeller, Jr., and consisted of leading figures in the fields of government, the performing arts, business, and education. Its principal function was to determine the status of the arts in American education through intensive surveys and research, thereby formulating comprehensive proposals for the integration of the arts with all aspects of school curricula. The panel issued its final report, entitled "Coming to Our Senses," in May 1977.
Upon the release of this report, Arts, Education and Americans, Inc. was incorporated on May 24, 1977, as a separate non-profit corporation to carry on the work started by the Panel.
Scope and Contents note
The records of the ACAE as received by the Rockefeller Archive Center are incomplete. Activities prior to 1974, including the Arts/Worth Program, are not intended to be documented in this collection. The records focus sharply upon the activities of the Arts, Education and Americans Panel, the preparation and issuance of its report, "Coming to Our Senses," and supporting research. Correspondence after 1977 deals almost exclusively with the distribution of the Panel report.
Included in the records of the AEAP are reports, correspondence, memoranda, research papers, transcripts of meetings or conferences, financial records and clippings. Users of this collection are advised that Series 4, the files of Norris Houghton (president of the ACAE, 1974-1976) may present the fullest and most accessible overview of the ACAE policies and activities during the period covered therein, as the organization did not issue annual reports. This collection is comprised of manuscript boxes, books, photographs, slides, audio tape recordings, videotapes, charts, and film.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IV 3B 12
Related Archival Materials note
See also the JDR 3rd Fund records.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The papers of The Arts, Education and Americans Panel of the American Council for the Arts in Education were deposited in the Rockefeller Archive Center on January 30, 1981.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Arts; Education; Arts -- Study and teaching; Art; Hunger; Arts, Education, and Americans Panel; American Council for the Arts in Education
- General Records, 1968-1978; 1; 0.4 Cubic Feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains correspondence regarding the Arts/Worth Program, background materials, and member organizations sponsoring the ACAE.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Arts/Worth Program, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Background Materials, 1968-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Background Materials, 1968-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Member Organizations, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Arts, Education and Americans Panel, 1972-1979; 2; 9.2 Cubic Feet
  This series consists of correspondence, reports, records of interviews, meetings and conferences, research papers and questionnaires, and staff records.
  This series is divided into five subseries:
  Subseries A - Correspondence: Speakers and Consultants
  Subseries B - Exemplary Site Investigations
  Subseries C - Financial Records
  Subseries D - Panel
  Subseries E - Research
  - Correspondence: Speakers and Consultants, A
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically, followed by a folder of form letters.
    - A-Fo (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - A-Fo (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - A-Fo (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Fowler, Charles, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Fo-Go (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Fo-Go (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Goodlad, John, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Gr-Hod (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Gr-Hod (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Hol-Mz (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Hol-Mz (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Hol-Mz (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Hol-Mz (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Hol-Mz (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Hol-Mz (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - N-R (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - N-R (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Rockefeller, David Jr., 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - S-Z (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - S-Z (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - S-Z (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Form Letters, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Exemplary Site Investigations, B
    This subseries includes records of interviews and visits to model school art programs.
    - Interviews, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Visits, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Visits, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Financial Records, C
    This subseries chiefly consists of records of insurance payments and publisher's bills.
    - Beneficial National Insurance Company, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Calvin Kytle Associates, 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Calvin Kytle Associates - Billing, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Calvin Kytle Associates - Billing, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - "Coming to Our Senses" - Bills, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Innovative Graphics International, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Returned (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - McGraw-Hill Book Company - Bills, 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Returned (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Returned (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Panel, D
    This subseries includes background materials on panel members and records of meetings and conferences.
    - Bibliography, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Background Material, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Consultants, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Members, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Members, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Witnesses (Artists), 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Witnesses (Educators), 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Meeting - Planning, September 9, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Meeting - Planning - Background and Opening/Closing Remarks, February 21, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Meeting - Planning - Correspondence and Preparatory Material, February 21, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Meeting - Planning - Discussion Groups I-III, February 21, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Meeting - Planning - Discussion Groups I-III, February 21, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Meeting - Planning - Discussion Groups I-III, February 21, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Meeting - Planning - Discussion Groups IV-V, February 21, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Meeting - Planning - Discussion Groups IV-V, February 21, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Meeting - Planning - Summary, February 21, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Meeting - Correspondence, June 27-28, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Meeting - Notebook, June 27-28, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Meeting - Correspondence, September 19-20, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Meeting - Notebook, September 19-20, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Meeting - Notebook, September 19-20, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Meeting - Background Materials (1), December 5-7, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Meeting - Background Materials (2), December 5-7, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 63)
    - Meeting - Notebook, December 5-7, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 64)
    - Meeting - Planning Arrangements, December 5-7, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - Meeting - Planning Arrangements, December 5-7, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 66)
    - Meeting - Planning Arrangements, December 5-7, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 67)
    - Meeting - Background Information on Community Programs, February 13-15, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 68)
    - Meeting - Notebook, February 13-15, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 69)
    - Meeting - Planning Information, February 13-15, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 70)
    - Meetings - Regional, April 1976 (Box 10, Folder 71)
    - Meeting - Arrangements, June 10-13, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 72)
    - Meeting - Background Information and Correspondence, June 10-13, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 73)
    - Meeting - Notebook, June 10-13, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 74)
    - Meeting - Transcript, June 10-13, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - Meeting - Transcript, June 10-13, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 76)
    - Meeting - Transcript, June 10-13, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 77)
    - Meeting - Transcript, June 10-13, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 78)
    - Meeting - Transcript Summary, June 10-13, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Meeting - Agenda and Transcript, September 15, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - Meeting - Arrangements, September 15, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 81)
    - Meeting - Arrangements, October 1-3, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 82)
    - Meeting - Materials for Panel Members, October 1-3, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 83)
    - Meeting - Notebook, October 1-3, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 84)
    - Meeting - Conference - Agenda Preparations, May 24-25, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 85)
    - Meeting - Conference - Arrangements, May 24-25, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 86)
    - Meeting - Conference - Arrangements, May 24-25, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 87)
    - Meeting - Conference - Invitation File, May 24-25, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 88)
    - Meeting - Conference - Invitation File, May 24-25, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 89)
    - Meeting - Conference - Invitation File, May 24-25, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 90)
    - Meeting - Conference - Invitation File, May 24-25, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 91)
    - Meeting - Conference - Materials for Panel Members, May 24-25, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 92)
    - Meeting - Conference - Press Kit, May 24-25, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 93)
    - Meeting - Conference - Speeches, May 24-25, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 94)
    - Meeting - Conference - Post-Conference Activities, May 24-25, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 95)
    - Meeting - Congressional Hearings - Correspondence, May 25, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 96)
    - Meeting - Congressional Hearings - Statements, May 25, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 97)
  - Research, E
    This subseries consists of background material on staff members, records of meetings, research papers, questionnaires and responses, and statistics drawn up by the research staff for use of the panel.
    - Background Papers (Box 14, Folder 98)
    - Book and Library Orders, 1975-1977 (Box 14, Folder 99)
    - Contracts, 1974-1976 (Box 14, Folder 100)
    - Design (Granville Meader), n.d. (c. 1974) (Box 14, Folder 101)
    - Education Resources Information Center (ERIC) Printout/Art Attitudes, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 102)
    - Meetings, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 103)
    - Meetings, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 104)
    - Memoranda, 1975-1977 (Box 14, Folder 105)
    - Paper - Acuff, Betty C. - "Arts Education and the Elementary School", 1976 (Box 14, Folder 106)
    - Paper - Acuff, Betty C. - "Arts Education and the Elementary School" - Draft, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 107)
    - Paper - Acuff, Betty C. - "Arts Education and the Elementary School" - Draft, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 108)
    - Paper - Acuff, Betty C. - "Exemplary Programs: Case Studies", 1976 (Box 15, Folder 109)
    - Paper - Acuff, Betty C. - "The Re-education of Arts Teachers (Secondary Level)", 1975 (Box 15, Folder 110)
    - Paper - Acuff, Betty C. - "Secondary Education", 1976 (Box 15, Folder 111)
    - Papers - Acuff, Betty C., 1976 (Box 15, Folder 112)
    - Papers - Baker, Terry L. - "Community Resources for the Arts in Education", 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 113)
    - Papers - Baker, Terry L. - "Teacher Training and Non-School Resources", 1975 (Box 15, Folder 114)
    - Papers - Baker, Terry L. - "Significant Non-School Resources in Arts Education", 1976 (Box 15, Folder 115)
    - Papers - Coe, Linda - "Federal Support for Arts Education", 1976 (Box 15, Folder 116)
    - Paper - Fowler, Charles - "Interviews....", 1976 (Box 15, Folder 117)
    - Papers - Freundlich, August - Drafts, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 118)
    - Papers - Freundlich, August, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 119)
    - Paper - Greenberg, Pearl - "The Re-education of Arts Teachers (Elementary Level)", 1976 (Box 16, Folder 120)
    - Paper - Hettinger, Cynthia M., 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 121)
      "Teacher Certification Requirements," 1975 "State Profiles," 1976
    - Papers - Hettinger, Cynthia M. - Background Material, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 122)
    - Paper - Landolfi, Carol - "The State of the Arts on Campus", 1976 (Box 16, Folder 123)
    - Paper - Melser, John - "Developmental Stages in Teaching the Arts", 1975 (Box 16, Folder 124)
    - Paper - Morea, Gina - "Teacher Training", 1975 (Box 16, Folder 125)
    - Paper - "Paradigm Samples", 1976 (Box 16, Folder 126)
    - Paper - Simmons, Joan H., 1976 (Box 16, Folder 127)
    - Progress Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 128)
    - Miscellaneous Questionnaires and Mailings, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 129)
    - NCSSM Questionnaire - Narrative Analysis, n.d. (c. 1975-1976) (Box 16, Folder 130)
    - Ohio Questionnaire - Interviews (A-H), 1975-1977 (Box 16, Folder 131)
    - Ohio Questionnaire - Interviews (A-H), 1975-1977 (Box 16, Folder 132)
    - Ohio Questionnaire - Interviews (Q-Z), 1975-1977 (Box 17, Folder 133)
    - Ohio Questionnaire - Summary of Results, 1975-1977 (Box 17, Folder 134)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Draft, 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 135)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Blank Forms, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 136)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Instructions to Interviewers, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 137)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - Appleton, Wisconsin, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 138)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - Atlanta County, Georgia, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 139)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - Brooks County, Georgia, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 140)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - Chippewa Falls, New York, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 141)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - Cobb County, Georgia, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 142)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - Glascock County, Georgia, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 143)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - Los Angeles, California, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 144)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - Madera, California, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 145)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - New Rochelle, New York, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 146)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - North Syracuse, New York, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 147)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - Palo Alto, California, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 148)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - Pittsburgh, California, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 149)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - Tuckahoe, New York, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 150)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - Watertown, New York, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 151)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - Wauwatosa, Wisconsin, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 152)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - West Allis, Wisconsin, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 153)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Schools - Summary, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 154)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Colleges (A-T), 1976 (Box 21, Folder 155)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Colleges (A-T), 1976 (Box 21, Folder 156)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Colleges (A-T), 1976 (Box 21, Folder 157)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Colleges (A-T), 1976 (Box 21, Folder 158)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Colleges (A-T), 1976 (Box 21, Folder 159)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Colleges (A-T), 1976 (Box 21, Folder 160)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Colleges (U-Z), 1976 (Box 22, Folder 161)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Colleges (U-Z), 1976 (Box 22, Folder 162)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - On-Site Interviews, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 163)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - On-Site Interviews, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 164)
    - Site Information Questionnaire - Summary (Acuff, Betty C.), 1976 (Box 22, Folder 165)
    - Staff Information, 1975-1977 (Box 22, Folder 166)
    - State Arts Councils, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 167)
    - State Arts in Education Program Survey (Alabama-Wisconsin), 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 168)
    - State Arts in Education Program Survey (Alabama-Wisconsin), 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 169)
    - State Arts in Education Program Survey (Alabama-Wisconsin), 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 170)
    - State Arts in Education Program Survey (Alabama-Wisconsin), 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 171)
    - State Arts in Education Program Survey (Alabama-Wisconsin), 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 172)
    - State Department of Education Questionnaire (Alabama-Wyoming), 1975-1976 (Box 23, Folder 173)
    - State Department of Education Questionnaire (Alabama-Wyoming), 1975-1976 (Box 23, Folder 174)
    - Statistics - Education, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 175)
    - Statistics - Intended for Conference, May 24-25, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 176)
    - Statistics - Low Enrollment/High Expenditure, n.d., c. 1976 (Box 24, Folder 177)
    - Statistics - Sample School Districts, n.d., c.1975 (Box 24, Folder 178)
    - Statistics - State Teacher Certification Requirements, n.d., c. 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 179)
    - Statistics - States, n.d., c. 1974 (Box 24, Folder 180)
    - Statistics - Status of the Arts Survey, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 181)
    - Statistics - Miscellaneous, 1971-1976 (Box 24, Folder 182)
- Panel Report, 1975-1978; 3; 4 Cubic Feet
  This series includes a copy of the report, "Coming to Our Senses," followed by all drafts and revisions made in its preparation. This is followed by a file of correspondence, reports, distribution records, mailing lists, and other material related to the preparation of this report.
  - Book - "Coming to Our Senses", 1977 (Box 24, Folder 183)
  - Draft - Front Matter, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 184)
  - Draft - Chapter I, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 185)
  - Draft - Chapter II, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 186)
  - Draft - Chapter II, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 187)
  - Draft - Chapter II, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 188)
  - Draft - Chapter III, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 189)
  - Draft - Chapter III, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 190)
  - Draft - Chapter III, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 191)
  - Draft - Chapter III, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 192)
  - Draft - Chapter III, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 193)
  - Draft - Chapter III, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 194)
  - Draft - Chapter III, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 195)
  - Draft - Chapter III, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 196)
  - Draft - Chapter IV, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 197)
  - Draft - Chapter V, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 198)
  - Draft - Chapter V, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 199)
  - Draft - Chapter V, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 200)
  - Draft - Chapter V, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 201)
  - Draft - Chapter V, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 202)
  - Draft - Chapter V, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 203)
  - Draft - Chapter VI, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 204)
  - Draft - Chapter VI, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 205)
  - Draft - Chapter VI, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 206)
  - Draft - Chapter VII, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 207)
  - Draft - Chapter VII, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 208)
  - Draft - Chapter VII, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 209)
  - Draft - Chapter VIII, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 210)
  - Draft - Chapter VIII, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 211)
  - Draft - Chapter VIII, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 212)
  - Draft - Chapter VIII, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 213)
  - Draft - Chapter IX, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 214)
  - Draft - Chapter IX, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 215)
  - Draft - Chapter IX, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 216)
  - Draft - Chapter X, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 217)
  - Draft - Chapter X, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 218)
  - Draft - Chapter X, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 219)
  - Draft - Chapter X, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 220)
  - Draft - Chapter X, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 221)
  - Draft - Appendices, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 222)
  - Draft - Appendix I, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 223)
  - Draft - Appendix II, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 224)
  - Draft - Footnotes (Chapters I-X), 1976 (Box 30, Folder 225)
  - Draft - Footnotes (Chapters I-X), 1976 (Box 30, Folder 226)
  - Draft - References, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 227)
  - Copyedited Manuscript, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 228)
  - Copyedited Manuscript, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 229)
  - Copyedited Manuscript, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 230)
  - Copyedited Manuscript, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 231)
  - Printers' Copy - Front Matter-Appendix/References, 1976-1977 (Box 31, Folder 232)
  - Printers' Copy - Front Matter-Appendix/References, 1976-1977 (Box 31, Folder 233)
  - Printers' Copy - Front Matter-Appendix/References, 1976-1977 (Box 31, Folder 234)
  - Printers' Copy - Front Matter-Appendix/References, 1976-1977 (Box 31, Folder 235)
  - Printers' Copy - Front Matter-Appendix/References, 1976-1977 (Box 31, Folder 236)
  - Printers' Copy - Credits/Index, 1976-1977 (Box 32, Folder 237)
  - Printers' Copy - Authors' Changes, 1976-1977 (Box 32, Folder 238)
  - Final Working Copy, 1976-1977 (Box 32, Folder 239)
  - Copyright File, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 240)
  - Distribution List - People and Programs Mentioned in Report, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 241)
  - Final Report Group, 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 242)
  - Mailing Lists, May-June 1977 (Box 32, Folder 243)
  - Mailing Lists, July 1977-January 1978 (Box 33, Folder 244)
  - Mailing Lists, July 1977-January 1978 (Box 33, Folder 245)
  - Mailing Lists, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 246)
  - Mailing List Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 33, Folder 247)
  - Mailing List Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 33, Folder 248)
  - Publication Schedule, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 249)
  - Publishers, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 250)
  - Publisher's Queries, 1976-1977 (Box 33, Folder 251)
  - Quotes, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 252)
  - Readers' Comments, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 253)
  - Rights and Permissions, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 254)
  - Rights and Permissions, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 255)
  - Rights and Permissions - Bills, 1976-1977 (Box 34, Folder 256)
  - Rights and Permissions - Visuals, 1976-1977 (Box 34, Folder 257)
  - Rights and Permissions - Visuals, 1976-1977 (Box 34, Folder 258)
  - Rights and Permissions - Working Papers, 1976-1977 (Box 34, Folder 259)
- Norris Houghton Files, 1958-1979; 4; 2.4 Cubic Feet
  This series includes correspondence, reports, records of meetings, and memoranda collected by Norris Houghton, president of the ACAE from 1974 to 1976.
  This series is divided into two subseries: